(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-06T00:40:12.243674",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
最近行ったのよ カラオケ。
I went to karaoke recently.
なんさ
You know,
2時間で解散と思うじゃん？
You'd think we'd split up after two hours, right?
そっからなのよ。
That's when it really gets going.
いろんなことできるわけ。
You can do all sorts of things.
やばいぞ！
It's awesome!
PLAY! NEW X. X PARK
X PARK最高！
X PARK is the best!
JOYSOUND X1
明太子をつくってよかった。
I'm glad we made mentaiko.
明太子が…
Mentaiko...
切子？切れ？
Kireko? Kire?
明太子が生まれ変わる新しい技を編み出しました！
We've created a new technique to reinvent mentaiko!
行きます！
Here we go!
ふくやの明太子から生まれたメンチーズシリーズ！
The Men-Cheese series born from Fukuya's mentaiko!
ピリリな味わい マコも大好き！
A spicy flavor, Mako loves it too!
詳しくはWebで！
Check the web for details!
My name is Hoshimachi Suisei,
and I'm singing the 3rd live tour song.
When you spell success, you create quite a promise for us girls,
and this song is stronger than anything else I could say.
It's called 'Te-ichi-no-yoru-o-koete'.
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ 演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Attention: Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance. Cheering loudly is OK.
受注生産グッズ①
Made-to-Order Goods ①
受注生産グッズ②
Made-to-Order Goods ②
受注生産グッズ③
Made-to-Order Goods ③
ライブグッズ販売開始
Live Goods Sales Start
本日は、星街すいせいライブツアー2024 SPECTRUM NOVAにご来場いただき、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Hoshimachi Suisei Live Tour 2024 SPECTRUM NOVA today!
星街すいせいです！
I'm Hoshimachi Suisei!
よろしくぅ！
Let's have a great time!
最後までライブを楽しんでいただくために、いくつかご案内させていただきますので、よく聞いておいてくださいね！
To ensure you enjoy the concert to the fullest, I have a few announcements to make, so please listen closely!
公演中の撮影・録音・録画機材の使用はお断りいたします。
The use of photography, audio, and video recording equipment during the show is strictly prohibited.
万が一、具合が悪くなってしまった場合は、無理をせず近くのスタッフへお知らせください。
Should you feel unwell at any point, please do not push yourself and notify a nearby staff member.
会場内でのモッシュ・ダイブ・ステージに物を投げ込むなど、他の皆さまの迷惑になったり公演を妨げる行為は一切禁止です。
Mosh pits, stage diving, throwing items on stage, or any behavior disturbing others or disrupting the show is strictly prohibited.
ルールを守って盛り上がってくださいね！
Please follow the rules and enjoy yourselves!
また、本公演は映像配信および写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、客席が映り込む場合がございます。これらはプロモーション等に使用される可能性がありますので、あらかじめご了承ください。
Additionally, cameras for video streaming and photography will be operating in the venue, and the audience may be captured. These may be used for promotional purposes, so please understand in advance.
また、ライブのハッシュタグは「かけめぐる星街」です。ハッシュタグを使ってたくさん盛り上げてくださいね！
Also, the live hashtag is #KakemeguruHoshimachi. Please use it to share the excitement!
それでは、わーい！
Now then, yay!
それでは、開演までもうすぐ！ドキドキしてきたみんなー！
Now then, the show is almost about to start! Is everyone getting excited?
みんなと一緒に盛り上がりましょう！ありがとうございました！
Let's all get hyped together! Thank you very much!
どんな建前も とても無理よ
"Any kind of pretense... I just can't do it,"
駆け引き上手の 大人にはなれないな
"I can't be an adult who's good at playing games."
なれないな
"I just can't."
そんな言葉 使用できない
"Those words are impossible to use."
限界まで 掻き出して いって
"Keep pushing to the limit,"
進化し続けるテクノロジー
"ever-evolving technology,"
伝えて 人肌のぬくもり
"Conveying the warmth of human skin."
ねぇ このまま ずっと
"Hey, just like this,"
降りやまない 雨の世界が
"in a world of endless rain,"
もう悲しくない 人は誰も
"it's no longer sad, because everyone"
生き物だから
"is a living being."
そう 白紙になった 青春の
"Yes, the blank page of youth"
残片 締め出すたっけ
"shuts out the fragments."
今 君に逢いたい と思う涙
"Now, tears of wanting to see you..."
本音も建前も 駆け引き上手な大人は 駄目だね
Adults skilled at playing both sides are no good,
そんな言葉 信用できない
I can't trust words like that.
便利で快適で 進化し続けるテクノロジー
Convenient, comfortable, ever-evolving technology,
伝えて 人肌のぬくもり
convey the warmth of human skin.
降り止まない 雨の世界だ
It's a world of unending rain.
もう悲しくない 人は慣れる生き物だから
I'm no longer sad, because humans adapt.
そう白紙になった 青春の何ページ目だったっけ
It became a blank sheet—what page of youth was that?
今、君に会いたいと 涙こみあげる
Tears well up wanting to see you now.
踏んだり蹴ったり 注意散漫 人生の転機だ
Ups and downs, distracted, it's life's turning point.
新しい時代を 乗りこなしていくんだ
Riding through a brand new era.
透明で 不鮮明で 叫び声あげるマイノリティ
Transparent, indistinct, a minority raising their voice,
健気に 失敗しては学んでく
bravely failing and learning from it.
降り止まない 雨の世界だ
It's a world of unending rain.
愛するしかない それしかない 器用じゃないから
I have no choice but to love; I'm not dexterous.
そう白紙になった 青春の何ページ目だったっけ
It became a blank sheet—what page of youth was that?
忘れ物思い出せないまま 忘れそう
I might forget without remembering what I left behind.
風の形見えない 見えないよ あなたが
The shape of the wind cannot be seen, you cannot be seen.
あなただって同じ
You're the same way too.
動き出すよ この身かけて 零さないよ
Set it in motion, risking this body, I won't let it spill.
泣いたってしょうがないさ
It's no use crying anyway.
降り止まない 雨の世界だ
It's a world of unending rain.
もう悲しくない 人は慣れる生き物だから
I'm no longer sad, because humans adapt.
そう白紙になった 青春の何ページ目だったっけ
It became a blank sheet—what page of youth was that?
今、君に会いたいと 涙こぼれて
Tears spill over wanting to see you now.
さよならだ さよならなんて認めたくないけど
I don't want to admit it's a final goodbye, but
雨上がりの この世界が眩しいから
because this post-rain world is so dazzling.
もう帰らない 振り返らない 思い出と共に
Never returning, never looking back, along with memories.
新しい風に煽られ そしてまた君に会いたいと願い
Swept by a new wind, wishing once more to see you.
駆けでゆく
Running onwards.
本音も建前も 駆け引き上手な大人は 駄目だね
Adults skilled at playing both sides are no good,
そんな言葉 信用できない
I can't trust words like that.
便利で快適で 進化し続けるテクノロジー
Convenient, comfortable, ever-evolving technology,
伝えて 人肌のぬくもり
convey the warmth of human skin.
降り止まない 雨の世界だ
It's a world of unending rain.
もう悲しくない 人は慣れる生き物だから
I'm no longer sad, because humans adapt.
そう白紙になった 青春の何ページ目だったっけ
It became a blank sheet—what page of youth was that?
今、君に会いたいと 涙こみあげる
Tears well up wanting to see you now.
踏んだり蹴ったり 注意散漫 人生の転機だ
Ups and downs, distracted, it's life's turning point.
新しい時代を 乗りこなしていくんだ
Riding through a brand new era.
透明で 不鮮明で 叫び声あげるマイノリティ
Transparent, indistinct, a minority raising their voice,
健気に 失敗しては学んでく
bravely failing and learning from it.
降り止まない 雨の世界だ
It's a world of unending rain.
愛するしかない それしかない 器用じゃないから
I have no choice but to love; I'm not dexterous.
気になるんだ
I'm curious...
そこに立つ私に
about myself standing there.
あぁ、あぁ
Ah, ah,
不可能なものはないの
nothing is impossible.
冗談だ
It's a joke.
鼻から絶賛で
Praised from the start,
それが常識と笑われても知らないんだ
I don't care if they laugh, calling it common sense.
口汚いペンスで払うわ 続くから
I'll pay in foul language, because it goes on.
世界をそっとくすぐれば
If you tickle the world gently,
燃えるほど
to the point of burning,
叫ぶほど
to the point of screaming,
ステージは熱くなる
the stage gets hot.
だからまだ不貞腐れをはり
So I still put on a sullen face,
ちゃんと声は届くから
my voice will properly reach you.
まだまだ声出せますよね！
Can you still raise your voices?!
いくぞ！
Let's go!
天井なくない？
Isn't there no ceiling?
燃え尽きたいだって
Wanting to burn out completely,
翼になって 心の真芯に
becoming wings, right at the heart's core,
同調してるんだろ
you're sympathizing, right?
あぁ、あぁ
Ah, ah,
リミット完全にぶっ壊して
completely shattering the limits,
つまり燃え尽きちゃえば
in other words, if you burn out,
不完全じゃなくなって歴史になるんだ
you become incomplete no more and make history.
そこに立つ私に
To myself standing there,
あぁ、あぁ 理由など可能な限り
Ah, ah, reasons as much as possible,
順調なんだよ
are going smoothly,
それだけなんだ
that's all there is.
適当な流口で 寒くないように
With a casual outlet, so you won't be cold,
知りたいならちょっと黙るか 道を開けろよ honey
if you want to know, shut up a bit or clear the way, honey.
世界をもっと狂わせて
Drive the world even more crazy,
燃え尽くして
burn it out completely,
burn it out completely.
着飾って頂上
Dressed up to the summit!
白いカーテンの sway 似たような朝のようで
White curtains swaying, like a similar morning,
まるで違う 交差する星彩 新しく目覚める
completely different, intersecting starlight, newly awakening
定型文の storyteller micは渡しちゃ駄目さ
You mustn't hand over the formulaic storyteller mic,
安全圏の observer error 何を信じる？
safe-zone observer error, what do you believe in?
眩しくて 逸らした初期衝動 今追随して
Dazzling, the initial impulse I averted, now following it.
空の愛の歌ばかりで もう聴き飽きてきたでしょ
You must be tired of hearing just empty love songs.
blackout 流星 knock down 寸前
Blackout, shooting star, right before knock down,
退屈してんじゃない？？
aren't you getting bored??
千載一遇の new senseで想像 光速の sympathyで
Imagine with a once-in-a-lifetime new sense, with light-speed sympathy,
直感主義の innocenceで創造 奇跡も世界も自分次第で！
Create with intuition-driven innocence, miracles and the world depend on yourself!
革命の狼煙は
The smoke signal of revolution is
変化を恐れない覚悟さ
the resolve not to fear change.
渇いた大地を駆ける唯一の光
The sole light running across the parched earth,
変わりたい・変えたいの連鎖が剥ぎ出しの魂を焚き付ける
the chain of wanting to change/make change kindles the bare soul.
6000万年に一度きりの surpriseでドラマティックな kissにしよう
Let's make it a dramatic kiss with a once-in-60-million-years surprise!
夜空に駆けた 遠すぎる欠片
Fragments running into the night sky, too far away,
光速超え 魅せられて まだ覚醒しない
surpassing the speed of light, charmed, not yet awakened.
惑星が導くレーダー
Radar guided by planets,
What do you need？ What do you take？
What do you need? What do you take?
望む場所へと
To the place you desire,
無謀な夢なら青天井 危ないほどアガる high-tension
If it's a reckless dream, the sky's the limit, high-tension rising the more dangerous it is.
突き抜ける銀河の果てで
At the edge of the piercing galaxy,
“Revolute-Meteor”
"Revolute-Meteor"
夢か現実か幻か ちゃんとその五感で確かめて hit me！
Dream, reality, or illusion? Confirm it properly with your five senses, hit me!
モニター越しの輝きじゃつまらない 飛び出す想像の遥か上 to heaven
The radiance through a monitor is boring, far above the soaring imagination, to heaven!
目を逸らさず見ていてね 自由への黎明
Keep watching without looking away, the dawn towards freedom!
踏み出した刹那 色付くnew days 絶景update
The moment I stepped out, coloring new days, scenic update,
希望も絶望も自分次第で！
hope and despair both depend on yourself!
革命の火蓋は
The opening of the revolution is
変化を望む強い情熱だ
a strong passion desiring change.
渇いた心に満ちた高潔な光
A noble light filling a parched heart,
壊しては創るの連続が 激動の未来を連れてくる
the succession of destroying and creating brings a turbulent future.
6000万年に一度きりの surpriseでドラマティックな kissにしよう
Let's make it a dramatic kiss with a once-in-60-million-years surprise!
モニター越しの輝きじゃつまらない
The radiance through a monitor is boring,
飛び出すその外なる gateway to heaven 目を逸らさず見ていてね
flying out to that outer gateway to heaven, keep watching without looking away.
銃口のレーダー 打ち鳴らせ high-tension
The muzzle's radar, ring out high-tension!
自由への黎明 色付くnew days 絶景 update
Dawn towards freedom, coloring new days, scenic update!
踏み出した刹那の落日 ごく自然に出来上がって
The sunset of the moment I stepped out, naturally completed,
昨日の自分死なないで
don't let yesterday's self die.
王道の革命の秘話は 札束を変化（かわ）のその表情で
The secret story of mainstream revolution, with a stack of bills in that expression of change,
語って
talk about it.
王道の革命の秘話は 札束を変化（か）えるその表情で
The secret story of mainstream revolution, changing a stack of bills with that expression,
語って 心に満ちた心の光
talk about it, the light of the heart filling the heart.
飛び出すその外なる gateway to heaven 目を逸らさず見ていてね
Flying out to that outer gateway to heaven, keep watching without looking away.
銃口のレーダー 打ち鳴らせ high-tension
The muzzle's radar, ring out high-tension!
自由への黎明 宇宙の連続が
Dawn towards freedom, the cosmic continuation,
光のほうへ未来を連れてくる
brings the future toward the light.
6000万年に一度きりの surpriseでドラマティックな kissにしよう
Let's make it a dramatic kiss with a once-in-60-million-years surprise!
Encount 夜空にかけた 遠すぎる欠片
Encount, fragments running into the night sky, too far away,
光速超え 魅せられて まだ覚醒しない
surpassing the speed of light, charmed, not yet awakened.
惑星が導くレーダー What do you need？ What do you take？
Radar guided by planets, What do you need? What do you take?
望む場所へと yeah yeah yeah yeah
To the place you desire, yeah yeah yeah yeah.
さいたま！
Saitama!
うぇ、ちょっと、頭3曲からぶち上がり、過ぎじゃないですか！
Ah, wait, jumping right from the third song, are you kidding me?!
はい、ということで、彗星のごとく現れたスターの星の奇跡、バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせい...
Now then, appearing like a comet, the VTuber star of miracles, Hoshimachi Suisei!
すいちゃんはー！
Suis-chan is...
今日も声がでかい。
Man, my voice is loud today.
今日もばっちりですよ、皆さん！
My voice is totally on point today, everyone!
いいじゃないですか！
Isn't that right?
ということで、星街すいせいライブツアー2024「Spectra of Nova」、いよいよ始まりましたー！
So, Hoshimachi Suisei Live Tour 2024 "Spectra of Nova" has finally begun!
ちょっと待って、1回、水飲むよ、ちょっと待って。
Hold on, let me take a sip of water real quick. Hold on.
ぶち上げすぎまして、私も。
I got a bit too hyped up myself.
いや、楽しいですね、やはりライブというものは。
Man, live shows are so much fun, aren't they?
今回初のライブツアーで、初日は、さいたまスーパーアリーナ...
And for our very first live tour, day one is... Saitama Super Arena!
でかい！
Huge!
もうね、あんなところまであの、お客さんがいて、見える？私のこと見える？
Man, we've got audience members way out there. Can you see me? Can you see me up there?
振って、振って、見える？
Wave, wave. Can you see?
あー、私も見えるよー！
Ah, I can see you too!
あ、もちもちもちも、あ、見えるよー！
Wave, wave, wave, wave. I can see you!
あ、なんかめちゃ聞こえる。「かわいい」って言った？
Oh, I hear someone shouting "cute."
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
さあ、皆さん、聞きなじみのない曲があったんじゃないですか？
Well, I'm sure you've all heard this song before, right?
昨日告知したんですけども、あの、新曲の「Awake」というものがですね、あ、出来上がりました！
I announced it yesterday, but my new song "Awake" is finally finished!
あ、んな感じです！
Such a cute song!
本日11月14日24時にデジタルリリースしますので、1日10回は聞いてくださいね、ここにいる皆さん。
It's going to be digitally released today, November 14th at 24:00, so everyone here, listen to it at least 10 times a day, okay?
そしてさらに、本日公演終了後にですね、「Awake」のMVを公開しちゃいます！
And furthermore, right after today's concert ends, we'll be releasing the MV for "Awake"!
この「Awake」のMVがね、なんかね、すごいギャル。
The MV for this "Awake" is just so... gurl!
あのね、すごいギャルなの。みんな見たらね、思うよ。おすいっちゃん、すごいギャルになった、すごいギャルになったって思うんで。
It's, like, super gurl. Everyone will think so once they see it.
かわいいわ。ギャルでもかわいい。ギャルでもかわいい。ありがとうございます。
It's cute. Well, it's gurl, but cute. Thank you very much.
じゃあ、ちょっとね、あの、スマ、スマホ持ってきてよ、スマホを。
Now, let me grab my smartphone.
ちょ、ここで、あの、プレミア公開の待機所を作ろうかなって思っちゃってる。
I was thinking about creating a waiting room for the premiere right now.
で、ちなみにこれ確認できるのは、配信のってみんなだげっていうね。
And by the way, the only ones who can check this are everyone watching the stream, right?
えー？だってみんな会場にいるみんなは今機内モードにしてるもんね、携帯ね。
Eh? Everyone in this venue is in airplane mode right now, so they can't use their phones, right?
じゃあ、行きますよ。えっとね、この上のとこなんで、上の
Okay, here we go. Let's see.
これどう？え？これで？これで？
How's this? Huh? How's this? How's this?
できてると？できてりるかな？わかんないよっ！
Is it working? Is it working? I have no idea!
そうだよよね。そうだよよね、会場にいるみんなわかんないよね。
Right? Of course, everyone in the venue wouldn't know either.
できたかな？
Did it work?
ちょっと、配信のコメント見るわ。
Let me check the live stream comments.
うーん。うーん。来た、来た。
Umm... Umm... It's coming, it's coming!
きてる、きてる、できてり、できてり、やったー！
It's working, it's working, it worked, it worked! Yay!
あ、できてららしいです、皆さん！わーい！
Ah, looks like it worked, everyone! Yay!
できてららしいわ。
Looks like it worked!
きちゃ。え、これ、プレミア公開にね、なってるんだよね。そうよね。
So, this is set to public premiere, right? Right?
できてり、できてり、きた。なでるらしいわ。はい。
It worked, it worked, it's here. Ah, looks like it's up, okay.
はい、これすいちゃんのスマホ。わーい！
So this is Suichan's smartphone. Yay!
かわいい。
Cute!
いえーい。
Yay!
はい。ありがとうございます。
Alright, thank you very much.
はい、ということで、なくなりました。
Alright, and with that, we're wrapping things up.
ちょっとね、みんなもね、帰ったら1日100回ぐらい聞いてくださいね。
So everyone, when you get home, make sure to listen to it about 100 times, okay?
お願いします！
I'm counting on you!
え、どうだった、ちなみに？めちゃよかった？
So, how was it? Was it good?
いえーい！ありがとうございます。
Yay! Thank you very much.
ちょっと、あの、初お披露目だったんで、緊張しながらだったんですが
Since I was revealing it for the first time, I was pretty nervous.
ということで、今回もバンドメンバーさんがいます！バンドさん！
And with that, we also have our band members here today! Let's hear it for the band!
セカンドに引き続きのメンバーでございます。一緒、ね、セカンドから一緒だったよね、みんなね。
They've been with us since the second album, right? We've been together since the second album, everyone, right?
あぁ、反応しちゃってる、ふふっ
Ah, it's reacting, hehe.
そして配信もあります！えぇ、推しカメラにアピール。はい。
And there's also a stream! Um,
appealing to the oshi camera. Yes.
パチコン！
Wink!
可愛いでしょう？
Isn't it cute?
なんと韓国でのライブビューイングも行われているそうです。
Apparently, live viewings are
also being held in Korea.
アンニョンハセヨ！みんなも、みんなも、はい、アンニョンハセヨ！
Annyeonghaseyo! Everyone too,
everyone too, yes, annyeonghaseyo!
バッチリ！
Spot on!
今回のライブの感想はハッシュタグかけめぐる星街でたくさんポストしてく
Please post your thoughts on today's concert
with the hashtag #KakemeguruHoshimachi,
ポスト、ツイートしてください！
post lots of them—post, tweet them!
YouTube、TikTokでご覧の方はここまでとなります！
For those watching on YouTube and TikTok,
this is where we part ways!
まだまだね、一緒に盛り上がりたいみんなは
Everyone who wants to keep getting hyped with us,
概要欄から配信サイトへ飛んでチケットを買ってください！お願いします！
please head to the streaming site from the description
and buy a ticket! Please!
では、そろそろ次の曲が聴きたいですよね？
Now then, you're ready to hear
the next song soon, right?
そうですよね？
Of course you are!
なんと今回ね、各所でそれぞれ違うセトリを用意してるんです。
And you know what? This time,
we've prepared different setlists for each location.
さあ、埼玉は次どの曲が来るのか、お楽しみに！
Now, Saitama, look forward to
seeing which song comes next!
無料パートは終了いたしました ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching.